Previously on "Transformers Prime..."
在上一集中
Bulkhead, where is Ratchet?
隔板 救护车人呢？
He's gone.
他被掳走了
If Megatron is truly rebuilding the Omega lock,
如果威震天真的想要重铸终极之锁
synthetic Energon might be a necessary component.
那么合成能量可能是一种不可或缺的原料
What did the cortical psychic patch yield?
大脑神经接入器获取了什么信息？
Only that the synthetic Energon formula is unstable.
只确认了合成能量的配方确实不稳定
If the transponder were still attached to Laserbeak,
如果应答器还在激光鸟身上
we could follow it.
我们就可以跟踪它
So, we're gonna let this doohickey fly back to 'Con central...
也就是说 我们要让这个小玩意飞回虎子的指挥中心
And lead us right to Ratchet.
并给我们指明救护车的位置
You would like to see the ruins of our devastated home world restored to their former brilliance.
你们应该期盼我们被毁灭的家园恢复昔日的辉煌吧？
You would just try to conquer Cybertron all over again.
你不过是想再次征服塞博特恩
But that does not change the fact
这个事实不会改变
that you may be Cybertron's only hope of ever seeing life again.
你或许是让塞博特恩重见天日的唯一希望
I'll do it.
我答应你
You sure we don't need to install a GPS on our scout here?
真的不用给侦察器装个GPS吗？
Too risky...
太冒险了
both sides are getting real good at rooting out that kind of trick.
这种小伎俩对双方来说 太容易识破了
Besides, we don't need a tracker.
况且 我们用不着追踪装置
We have Optimus.
我们有擎天柱
But won't the 'Cons see you coming, big guy?
但虎子不会发现你吗 大块头？
Not until it's too late.
等他们发现时已经晚了
We'll be prepared for immediate mobilization upon your command, sir.
我们会做好准备 接到命令立即行动 长官
Good luck, Optimus.
祝你好运 擎天柱
Be safe.
注意安全
Whatever the outcome,
无论结局如何
know that Ratchet would be most proud of your contribution.
相信救护车一定会为你们的努力而骄傲
Come on, kid. Let's light this thing.
来吧 孩子 把这玩意儿送上天
Fetch me the quantum-cyber measure.
把量子-数字测量仪给我拿来
Hmm.
哼
Do I look like hired help to you, Autobot?
我像是给你打下手的吗 汽车人？
Knockout, attend to the needs of our esteemed guest.
击倒 必须满足贵客的要求
As you command.
遵命…
So, we know this cyber matter to be produced
已经得知 这种塞博特恩网状物
by an atypical molecular-displacement reaction.
是非典型分子置换反应的产物
Extensive empirical evidence indicates
大量实验证据表明
the fundamental instability within the Synth-En formulation to be the cause.
合成能量配方的不稳定性是问题的根源
Double-blind analysis?
双盲分析做了吗？
Naturally. The results only confirmed my original hypothesis.
当然 实验结果只是证实了我最初的假设
Once the erroneous variable has been corrected for,
一旦修正了错误变量
the stabilized synthetic material will bind properly with cybernucleic acid.
稳定的合成物将会与C.N.A.完美结合
And produce a stable form of cyber matter.
从而产生稳定的塞博特恩网状物
Remarkable.
不可思议
Yes. Quite an act of providence.
没错 似乎是天意
And to think that, had we not let you destroy the beasts,
知道吗 要不是让你们干掉了那些野兽
none of this would be possible.
也不会取得今天的成果
Let?
“让”我们？
Uh, what I meant to say was...
我是说…
those specimens you requested earlier aren't going to prepare themselves, are they?
你之前索要的样本可不会凭空蹦出来 是吧？
There is much to do and little time, Doctor.
任务艰巨 时间紧迫 医生
Shall we get back to work?
该继续工作了吧？
Certainly.
当然
Prime. Haven't heard from you in a while.
擎天柱 你消失有一阵子了
Everything all right up there?
一切还顺利吗？
So far, Agent Fowler.
目前还好 福勒探员
What happens when the 'Cons I.D. Laserbeak's signal?
虎子识别了激光鸟的信号后会怎样？
We're counting on Optimus making visual contact with the warship
只希望擎天柱能尽快看到战舰
before its radar can detect the ship.
赶在被雷达发现之前
The boss will be fine.
老大不会有事的
It's not Optimus I'm worried about.
我担心的并不是擎天柱
Knockout. I require a fresh CNA sample.
击倒 我需要一个新鲜的C.N.A.样本
Ohh, I...
噢…我…
"Knockout, bring this. Knockout, get that."
击倒 把这个拿来 击倒 把那个给我
Apparently, fetching is all I'm good for lately.
很显然 取货成了我的新特长
It wasn't all that long ago I used to run this lab.
不久前 我还是这个实验室的老大
Now I am everyone's gofer.
现在人人都拿我当跑腿儿的使唤
Yes?
有事么？
The... the isoprobe!
绝缘探针！
I-I... don't see one.
我…没找到
What a surprise.
我就知道…
Ohh.
哦
Anything else?
您还要点什么？
Thank you.
谢谢
You're welcome.
不客气
We stand at the very precipice of a new age!
我们即将进入一个新纪元！
What do you mean, our scanners have detected Laserbeak's Signal?
你是说扫描器探测到了激光鸟的信号？
Starscream.
红蜘蛛
You did destroy the Autobot base,
你不是摧毁汽车人基地了吗？
did you not?
有漏网之鱼吗？
With great fervor, my lord.
已经夷为平地了 陛下
Why do you ask?
您何出此言？
Because Laserbeak's frequency has been detected on radar.
激光鸟的通讯频率出现在了雷达上
But that's not possible.
这不可能！
He's right here in Soundwave's torso.
他不就在声波的胸前吗
Which is why this would appear to be an Autobot trick
也就是说 这应该是汽车人耍的诡计
designed to uncover our position and rescue a certain prisoner.
目的是查探我们的位置 营救那个俘虏
But then one has to wonder
不过 我倒想问问
how would they possibly manage to execute such a complex task
他们怎么可能实施如此复杂的行动？
without the proper facilities!
现在他们连基本设施都没有！
I, uh...
我…呃…
Allow me to troubleshoot.
请允许我去查明原委
Oh... The final piece of the puzzle.
哦…谜题的最后一环
Thank you, Decepticon engineering.
多谢了 霸天虎工程技术
Shockwave!
震荡波
Assembly of the Omega lock is  entering the final stage.
终极之锁的组装已进入最终阶段
Your guidance is required.
我需要你前去指导
Understood, my liege.
遵命 我的君王
Knockout, supervise our guest in my absence.
击倒 我不在时你来监督客人
Wow. Thanks for the big vote of confidence.
哇 我真是受宠若惊
I can't allow Megatron to possess the stabilized formula.
我决不能让稳定的配方落到威震天手中
Not now...
现在不行
or ever.
以后也不行
For the love of... what is happening?!
我的天啊 出什么事了？
The formula's instability...
配方不稳定…
it must have triggered a chain reaction!
一定是引起了连锁反应！
Guards, help me extinguish this inferno
卫兵 快来帮我灭火
before it scorches the project...
不然它会烧毁我们的项目…
And my finish!
还有我的涂装！
Optimus Prime!
擎天柱！
How dare you continue to live?
你竟敢苟活于世！
Blast that Autobot into oblivion!
给我把那个汽车人轰成碎片！
The frequency isn't emanating from Prime,
那个频率并非来自擎天柱
and it's still on the move.
而且还在移动
Finish him!
干掉他！
If I cannot find the source of the signal before it finds the warship,
如果不能在信号源发现战舰之前找到它
Megatron will have our heads!
威震天会要了我们脑袋的！
Lord Megatron,
威震天陛下
Uh, there has been a situation...
呃 出了点小麻烦
Uh, more like an accident, really. I...
呃 其实是个小事故 我真的…
Spit... it... out!
别绕弯子！
The prisoner has escaped!
俘虏逃跑了！
Come out, come out, wherever you are.
现身吧 现身吧 别藏了
Not bad for an old bot.
这把老骨头还挺灵活
If you terminate me,
如果你杀了我
you'll never get your hands on the formula!
你就永远也得不到配方！
Oh, I wouldn't be so certain, Doctor.
哦 别把话说那么绝 医生
My experts are working diligently to disentangle your...
我们的专家正在努力揭开你的…
false trail as we speak.
装模作样的面具
There you are.
找到了
And down you go.
给我下去吧
No!
不！
Aah! I need a ground bridge... now!
啊！我需要环陆桥 快！
Tsk, tsk, tsk. Nice try.
啧 啧 啧…想得美
I'll just put this back where it belongs.
我还是把它放回原处吧
Spectrum analysis confirms
频谱分析确认
that the synthetic Energon is stable.
合成能量已经稳定
The formula is now complete.
配方制作完毕
And your timetable for production?
什么时候能开始生产？
With the aid of hyper-acceleration technology,
有了超级加速科技的协助
not long.
不会太久
Ohh, a pity you won't live long enough to witness the fruits of your labor.
哦 可惜你无法眼看着自己的研究成果开枝散叶
But as much as we appreciate your contributions, Doctor,
尽管我很感激你做出的贡献 医生
I've made a promise to someone that I intend to keep.
但我有个诺言必须要兑现
Do you feel defenseless, Autobot?
你是不是感到回天无力 汽车人？
Good. Now you know what my fellow Predacons endured...
很好 现在你知道 我的巨狰狞弟兄们
right before you massacred them!
被你们屠杀前作何感受了！
Optimus to base... come in.
擎天柱呼叫基地 请回答
Commander, have you determined the warship's location?
指挥官 你已经确认了战舰位置吗？
No, Ultra Magnus.
没有 通天晓
The transponder has been destroyed.
应答器被毁掉了
We are no closer to finding Ratchet than when we began.
寻找救护车的任务几乎退回了原点
Lord Megatron,
威震天陛下
synthesis of the cyber matter required to cyberform Earth has commenced.
数字化地球所需的塞博特恩网状物已开始合成
Splendid, Shockwave!
干得漂亮 震荡波！
Move the Omega lock into position.
把终极之锁移动到指定位置
I want to be ready.
我要做好一切准备
At last, good riddance to a wretched species.
终于 可以摆脱这个悲惨的种族了…
Although I will say they manufacture some fine-looking automobiles.
值得一提的是他们倒很擅长制造帅气的车辆
Just get it over with.
给我个痛快吧
It's not like I could ever live with myself,
我也没脸活下去了
knowing the role I played in humankind's extinction.
现在我成了人类灭绝的帮凶
But if you want to avenge your cohorts,
但如果你想为同伴报仇
don't stop with me!
杀掉我并不是终点！
Keep avenging all the way to Megatron!
威震天才是你的最终目标！
What?! What do you mean?!
什么？！你什么意思？！
Your high and mighty leader wanted your Predacons exterminated...
是你那高高在上的首领 想要除掉你们巨狰狞
and simply allowed us to do his dirty work for him!
我们仅仅是他的棋子而已！
Nothing but a false claim to save your own spark!
你是为了保命才信口开河！
Hea...
咳
You consider yourself an intelligent being, don't you?!
你自认为是智慧生物 不是吗？！
Then rise above your base instincts...
那就放下你的野兽本能
and analyze the situation.
分析当时的情况
We followed the trail that day with the desperate hope
那天我们拼命地追查
that it would lead to an Energon mine.
只希望能找到一座能量矿
We had no idea we would find Shockwave's laboratory.
从没想过会发现震荡波的实验室
The coincidence barely seems plausible!
这个巧合太离谱了！
Because it wasn't a coincidence.
因为那根本不是巧合！
The Energon was clearly planted to lure us there...
故意用能量引诱我们过去的…
by Megatron!
就是威震天！
Why would my liege wish to destroy us?
我的君王为何要毁灭我们？
Having just been on the receiving end of your might,
在见识过你的强大本领之后
one theory springs to mind...
我忽然有了个想法…
Megatron fears you
威震天惧怕你
and any like you.
还有你的同类
Lord Megatron, Predaking is on a rampage and moving rapidly... toward the...
威震天陛下 冲云霄在大开杀戒
Autobot base, do you read?
汽车人基地 能收到吗？
This is Ratchet. Can anyone hear me?
我是救护车 有人能听到吗？
Loud and clear, old friend.
清晰无比 老朋友
- Whoo - hoo! - Yes! Ratchet!
- 太好了！ - 是救护车！
I knew he was all right!
我就知道他没事！
Listen to me...
听我说
Megatron has managed to rebuild the Omega lock on board his warship.
威震天设法在他的战舰上重建了终极之锁
I've deactivated the Decepticon shielding system.
我已经关闭了霸天虎的护盾
You should be able to get a fix on my coordinates.
你们应该可以定位我的坐标
Optimus, you must hurry!
擎天柱 必须尽快行动！
Megatron is preparing to cyberform Earth as we speak!
威震天正准备把地球数字化 十万火急！
Ratchet...
救护车…
Autobots, lock on to those coordinates
汽车人 锁定坐标
and prepare to storm the warship.
准备突袭战舰
You heard our leader.
领袖下令了
We're going in, and we're going in heavy.
既然要打 就战个痛快！
Gear up.
武装起来！
They can't leave without saying goodbye.
他们也不知道告个别
No time for that, and no need.
没时间了 也没有必要
They'll be back.
他们会回来的
Initiating groundbridge.
开启环陆桥
Members of team Prime,
领袖卫队的成员们
Autobot and human,
汽车人和人类朋友
it has been my honor to lead you.
能领导你们我深感荣幸
On this day, the fates of two worlds hang in the balance,
今时今日 两个世界的命运岌岌可危
and the battle to come may very well be our last.
而这场战役很可能是我们的最后一战
But for Earth, for Cybertron,
为了地球 为了塞博特恩
for our comrade, Ratchet,
为了我们的战友救护车
we must take the Decepticon warship.
我们必须攻下霸天虎的战舰
Are you sure confronting the beast-bot directly
您确定和那个半兽人正面对决
is the best option, lord Megatron?
是明智之举吗 威震天陛下？
We shall see how his majesty
让我们看看 这位自封的王者
fares against the most powerful weapon in our vault...
如何应付我们手中最强大的武器…
the Dark Star Saber!
黑暗星辰剑！
Megatron!
威震天！
I'll just go fetch that little something we talked about.
我这就去取刚才提到的那个小玩意儿
Is it true that you ordered the annihilation of my army?!
真的是你下令毁灭我的野兽大军吗？！
Indeed, and my only mistake was not seeing the extermination through.
确实如此 而我唯一的错误就是没有斩草除根
I will tear you apart!
我要把你大卸八块！
I... aah!
我…啊！
That's the spirit.
表现不错
But I was a champion of the pits of Chaon
但作为卡隆角斗场的冠军
not only due to my savage might...
我拥有的不仅是蛮力…
but also my cunning!
还有脑子！
You should have heeded my advice and faced me as a beast.
你该听从我的忠告 在我面前保持野兽形态
Bravo, my liege.
太精彩了 我的君王！
It isn't every day one witnesses the extinction of a species all over again.
这可不是常有的事 见证已经绝迹的种族再遭灭顶！
One ultimate weapon coming right up.
终极武器登场喽！
Uh, where's tall, dark, and scaly?
呃 满身鳞片的黑大个哪儿去了？
Report.
汇报情况！
Lord Megatron, the ship is under attack...
威震天陛下 战舰正遭受攻击
by the Autobots.
是汽车人
But the warship is cloaked.
战舰不是处于隐形状态吗
How is that possible?
这怎么可能？
The medic lives!
那个军医还活着！
Mobilize what remains of our forces!
动用所有剩余力量！
The Omega lock must be defended at all costs!
全力保护终极之锁 不惜一切代价！
If Optimus Prime wishes to wage a battle
如果擎天柱想主动开战
for the fate of both Earth and Cybertron...
赌上地球和塞博特恩的命运
then I shall oblige him.
那么我就如他所愿
This will be our last stand!
在此与他决一死战！